Guide to the Frank Mack papers, 1980s-1990s
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Frank Mack papers
1980s-1990s
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Frank Mack
C0058
4.5 linear ft.; 9 boxes
Collecton containes correspondence, memos, reports and other papers generated by Frank Mack.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Arena Stage in 2000.
Historical Information
Arena Stage was an early leader in the resident theater movement. One of the first not-for-profit theaters in the United States as well as a pioneer of the regional theater movement the Arena Stage was the first regional theater to transfer a production to Broadway, the first invited by the U.S. State Department to tour behind the Iron Curtain and the first to receive a Tony Award. Co-founded in 1950 by Edward Mangum a teacher from the George Washington University, and Zelda Fichandler one of his students, Arena Stage was opened in Washington D.C. to fill the void left by the closing of the National Theater in 1948. Deriving it's name from the idea of "theater in the round," Arena Stage became one of the first resident theaters in the United States, beginning with a company of only eight actors. Today, Arena performs to over 250,000 patrons during a September to June season and employs nearly 200 theater professionals and craftpersons, who are responsible for all the costumes and scenery seen on stage. Many now- famous actors took part in Arena Stage productions during the early part of their careers. Some of them include Robert Prosky, Morgan Freeman, Dianne Weist, James Earl Jones, Kevin Kline, Christopher Guest, Yeardly Smith and Samuel L. Jackson.
A native of Kansas, Mr. Mack graduated from the University of Kansas in Lawrence in 1985 with a bachelor's degree in theatre arts then earned an MFA in directing from Virginia Tech in Blacksburg in 1988. Mr. Mack was awarded a grant from the North Carolina Arts Council, which enabled him to work in community arts administration at Durham Arts Council, Inc. He then accepted a position at Arena Stage in Washington DC as Project Manager where, in addition to general administrative duties, he worked on a three-year new play project with Anna Deavere Smith that resulted in the fall 1997 premiere of House Arrest, First Edition. Mr. Mack was then named Managing Director of the California Shakespeare Theatre in Berkeley where he helped lead a financial turn-around based on a doubling of contributed income and a substantial increase in ticket sales. Mr. Mack then served as Managing Director of Geva Theatre in Rochester, NY, a LORT B theatre before he became Managing Director of the NJ Shakespeare Festival in Madison, NJ, where he worked for one year before coming to CRT. Mr. Mack served as an institutional planning consultant for the Contemporary American Theatre Festival in Shepherdstown, WV and as a panelist for the Connecticut Commission for the Arts, and is currently serving as a facilities and business plan consultant to the African Continuum Theatre Company in Washington, D.C. He lives in Mansfield Center with his wife, Sarah Delia, and their two children Jason, Rebecca and their dog Chili.
Scope and Content
Collecton containes correspondence, memos, reports and other papers generated by Frank Mack.
Arrangement
Organized by subject.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives holds the Arena Stage records.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Arena Stage (Organization: Washington, D.C.)
Subjects:
Theater--Washington (D.C.)
Contents List
- Frank Mack papers
  - Dancing at Lughnasa (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee Files: 1992 - 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Student Matinee Series (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Budget: 1991 - 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Financial Reports: Fiscal Year 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Budget: Fiscal Year 1994 (Income) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Budget: Fiscal Year 1994 (general) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brainstorming Sessions 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Board of Trustees: 1992 - 1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 5 year plan: 1986 - 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Financial Statements: 1988 - 1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Individual Bound Statements.
  - Future Plan 1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - London tour 1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Marketing Survey 1986 - 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Marketing Survey - Abramson Research (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Senior Staff Retreat: 6/29/88 - 6/30/88 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 40th Anniversary FR/Events firms 1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 40th Anniversary 1989 - 1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Managing Director (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Arena Stage study of Operations: May 1979 - September 1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Marketing Advison CT (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Administration (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Building Management (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Arena Stage building designs by Harry Weese (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Development Director Search 1990 - 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Howard County Arts Council 1989: Joesph Zeilgler Questionaire (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - George Mason University Federal Theater Project February 1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - DC Bicentennial Commission September 1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - NEA - Arts Plus Program (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Teacher's Focus Groups: 10/3/1992 andamp; 11/21/92 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - DC Tax Exemption Filing 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Living Stage, Kreeger, Arena Parcels
  - DC property tax exemption Report 1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - DC property tax exemption forms 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - DC property tax exemption report 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - DC property tax exemption forms 1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - George De Vincent photography 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cultural Alliance files 1987 - 1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - AIE-TGC general program information (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Arts in Education - Funding (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - America 2000 - Arts Partnership (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Arts in Education - Council for Basic Education (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Arts in Education - Meetings October 29, 1992; November 5, 1992; November 12, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Arts in Education meeting minutes - October 11, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Arts in Education meeting minutes - December 29, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Arts in Education - Arena Stage in-house memos and notes (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Arts in Education - Mitchell Korn info and Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Arts in Education - program development (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Arena Stage's Pan and Mission meeting minutes (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Suzuki - budget (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Suzuki Project (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "Beehive" production information (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Society of Stage Directos and Choreographers 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Society of Stage Directors and Choreographers Directory (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Society of Stage Directors and Choreographers Directory (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Society of Stage Directors and Choreographer Strike 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - League of Resident Theaters - Society of Stage Directors and Choreographers agreement 1985 - 1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - DC Commission (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - United Scenic Artists agreement 1987 - 1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Equity Rule Books - League of Resident Theaters (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - League of Resident Theaters 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - LORT / SSDC negotiations 1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Pear, fagan and Bormel Audit (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - NEH grant program 1990 - 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - New Voices/Common Ground 1992 - 1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - D andamp; O Insurance March 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - DC Commission on the Arts ,Major Institution Grant 1988 - 1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Ford Foundation 1991 -1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Jr. Gang Meetings 1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Metro Stop (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - National Captial Arts grant Fiscal Year 1990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - National cultural Alliance: June, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - New general Correspondence 1991 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - NEH New Scholars Grant 1991 - 1992 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - NEA 1992 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Managment Consultants for the Arts, Inc. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - AATE/ETA - Task Force on Standards K - 12 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Naational Association for Schools of theater (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - AIE - Selected Bibliographies of General Information (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - NEA Challenge III Grant March, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Organizational Chart- Pre Ham 1991 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Nominating Committee 1992 - 1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Investment Committee Fiscal Year 1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Finance Committee 1992 - 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Development Committee 1991 - 1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - CSAP Grant Proposal: Living Stage (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Arts in Education job description (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - American Allienance for Theatre and Education (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Communication Committee 1992 - 1993 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Study Summary: understanding how the arts contribute to excellent education (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Arts in Education Proposal (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Executive Committee 1991 - 1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Development/Communications Joint Step Meeting 1991 - 1992 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Development Budget Tracking Report 1991 - 1992 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Investment Committee 1990 - 1991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Finance Committee 1990 - 1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Executive Leadership Committee 1990 - 1991 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Board - AS (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Communications Committee 1990 - 1991 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Development Committee 1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Fellows Program - AS (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Community Outreach Advisory Committee 1991 - 1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Allen Lee hughes Fellows 1990 - 1991 program (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Long Range Planning Committee 1990 - 1991 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Public Sector Outreach Committee 1991 -1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Long Range Planning Committee 1992- 1993 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - American Arts Alliance 1985 - 1989 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - American Arts Alliance 1992 - 1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - American Arts Alliance (general info) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Accessability 1990 - 1991 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Living Stage (general files) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Arts international/Russian intern (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - AtandT: On Stage (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - The Arnea Arrow Newsletter 1991 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Computer Development (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Bessemer Trust Company october 1990 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Audience Response 1990 - 1991 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Chernikoff andamp; Company 1988 - 1991 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Rose Cowen (NYU student) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - the Coca-Cola Foundation (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Coolfont Resort project (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Campaign Investment Portfolio (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Investment Advisor Search (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Stackig Sanderson and White (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - DC schools outreach, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - DC public schools, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - DC public schools, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Black Ivy program (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - teacher workshops: 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "The Glass Menagerie", study guide (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - student matinee program: 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - DC Schools: 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - "Trinidad Sisters", reception and outreach (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "Juno and the Paycock", Irish reception and outreach (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "From the Missisippi Delta", correspondence (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - "My Children, My Africa", correspondence (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Arena Stage season, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - "A Mid-Summer's Night Dream", study guide and correspondence (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - "Playboy", correspondence (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - "Les Blancs", general information (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - misc. correspondence (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - community outreach advisory committee: 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - 'Know your political arena', correspondence (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Arena Stage Church Angels program, correspondence (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Signature Series; general information (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Hispanic Caucus events (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Signature Series program (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Signature Series program (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Signature Series program (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Signature Series program (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Ring Round the Moon, opening night response list (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - African American, Signature Series (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Black History, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Signature Series - The Caucasian Chalk Circle (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Signature Series - Jar the Floor (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Signature Series - On the Town (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Signature Series - Shakespear (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Signature Series - Merrily We Roll Along (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Signature Series - The Glass Menagerie (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Signature Series - Yerma (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Signature Series - Revolutionary Politics (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Signature Series - Brothers Under the Skin (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Signature Series - What Mama Wished (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Signature Series (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Community Outreach Committee (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Arena 2-Nite; 1991 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Latino outreach (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - student matinee series; 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - volunteer - general info (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - arts in edu: 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - volunteer time sheets (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Watherfront - correspondnce (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Arena Stage hands (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Jamaican Relief (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - student matinee extra's; 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - The Arena Arrow, Fall 1991 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - LRP retreat (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - LRP stuff - sent to full BD (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Staff retreat (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - artistic plan for Arena Stage (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - artistic statement and financial information for the Living Stage (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Arena Stage long range plan draft statement (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - long range plan committee meeting, Feb. 13th 1992 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - long range plan memo, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - long range plan, senior staff meeting minutes, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - long range planning notes, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Doug Wager speeches, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - National Theatre Artisit Residency (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - subscription surveys, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - staff retreat 1993 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - correspondence: Stephen Richard, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - long range plan; December draft (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - long range plan sent to board, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - long range plan sent to board, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Long Range Plan, draft 1991 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Long Range Plan draft, Oct. 1991 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Long Range Plan, draft (Box 14, Folder 6)